onnanoko hajimemashita
A tired girl starts her day
tameiki wa bioron no shirabe ni nite
With a sigh like the moan of a violin
akai mi hajikechatta
A cherry bursts in her mouth
mada anata wo shiranai
This was before we had met
konna koto hajimetette
This is the first time I've ever felt like this
manazashi wa aku no hana sakimidarete mo
I could see that your pretty eyes were filled with contempt
ie e to tsuzuku
But I had to go home
basu sutoppu demo anata wa tsurenai
Even at the bus stop, you gave me the cold shoulder
karameta hanabi myaku utsu
The fireworks in the sky pulse
koi no shiruetto
In a silhouette of love
karui mahou
With a little magic,
usotsuki na kuchibiru
Two sets of lying lips
sou kasaneteru
Lock together
ano ne
You see
nee kamisama
God...
warui ko ni naritai yo
I'd like to be a naughty girl
ii ko ni shiteru kara
I'm tired of being good
onegai dayo
So, please
zurui koto sasetoite
It's for a good reason
ii koto shitai nara
So let me be bad for once
sukaato hirogaesu shite
By flipping my skirt
sugu kaeru yo
I'll be back soon
doyoubi wa haresou da
It looks like Saturday is going to be sunny
kamisama hajimemashita
God, it has already started
Momozono Nanami
High School Student
Seventeen Years Old
Momozono Nanami. High school student.
（鳴神姫(なるかみひめ)）
“桃園(ももぞの)奈々生(ななみ) 女子高生”
This girl is hardly more than a child. How did she become the god of the Mikage Shrine?
（鳴神姫）
どうして こんな娘が
ミカゲ社の神になっているのです？
Where has Mikage gone?
ミカゲはどこへ？
His whereabouts have been
unknown for twenty years now.
（乙比古(おとひこ)）
20年も前から行方知れずよ
家出？
Unknown?!
Will you give me Tomoe, please?
巴衛(ともえ) 頂戴
I'd rather not.
（ミカゲ）
嫌です
He refuses to give me Tomoe, and then he disappears for twenty years?!
とか言っといて
20年も行方知れず？
You have to feel sorry for poor Tomoe.
Curse that man! He stole Tomoe from me!
（乙比古）
巴衛君 かわいそうよね
人間の神使なんて
（鳴神姫）
おのれ あの男
（乙比古）
巴衛君 かわいそうよね
人間の神使なんて
私から巴衛を奪って…
How awful to serve a human.
He will pay!
（鳴神姫）
許せん…
Momozono Nanami.
（鳴神姫）
桃園奈々生
Are you worthy of being a god?
あなたが
神にふさわしい人間かどうか―
I, Lady Narukami, god of thunder, shall be the judge of that.
この雷神 鳴神姫が
見定めてあげましょう
The God Loses Her Home
Seven lightning strikes to the east...
（巴衛）
東のほうに落雷７つか
It must be that time of the month for Narukami.
鳴神が また
かんしゃくを起こしているな
It's getting closer and closer.
（虎徹(こてつ)）
だんだん近づいてきております
By the looks of it, she's heading this way.
あの様子では ここに来るな
I overslept!
（奈々生）
寝坊した！　巴衛
どうして起こしてくれないのよ
Tomoe, why didn't you wake me up?!
やっと起きたか
So you're finally awake.
Today's breakfast is rice porridge with a thick Yoshino kudzu sauce and sesame tofu made by yours truly.
今日の朝食は
吉野葛(よしのくず)あんかけ 朝がゆに…
（巴衛）巴衛特製ごま豆腐
（奈々生）ごめん 食べてる暇ない
Sorry, no time to eat!
Hold it.
（巴衛）待て
（奈々生）えっ
You're forgetting your lunch and head gear.
弁当と額当てを忘れているぞ
Don't need them.
いらない
Just put it on!
（巴衛）
いいから着けろ
私 戦いに行くんじゃないもん
学校に勉強しに行くんだもん
I'm not going out there to fight! I'm going to school to learn!
There's a visitor coming to the shrine today.
今日は社に客が来る
俺は ここから離れられない
Therefore, I cannot step away from here.
お前が心配なのだ
I'm worried for you.
Because you are...
お前が―
as weak as a bug.
虫けらのように弱いから
（奈々生）
いってきます
I'm going.
（巴衛）
奈々生！
Nanami!
Sheesh! He's such a worrywart!
（奈々生）
もう 心配性なんだから
Huh?
あら ひと雨来そうだよ
Looks like it's gonna rain.
（講釈師）
奈々生ちゃん
神様修行も学校生活も―
Dear Nanami's training as a god and her school life are both going swimmingly!
順調～
…のはずでございましたが―
Or so we wish, but things aren't looking so good.
こりゃまた雲行き怪し　怪しすぎ
Not good at all.
I heard Kurama isn't feeling well, so he's not coming to school.
（海辺(うみべ)）
鞍馬(くらま)様 今日は―
体調不良で休みだって
（飛田(とびた)）ええっ どよーん
（奈々生）わっ
What? Bummer!
What?!
Lady Nanami.
（鬼切(おにきり)･虎徹）奈々生様
（奈々生）鬼切君 虎徹君
Onikiri! Kotetsu!
ああっ ええっ
どうして かばんの中に？
Why are you in my bag?!
We are here on Master Tomoe's orders.
（虎徹）
巴衛殿に仰せつかってまいりました
（鬼切）
今日一日は 我ら鬼火わらしが
奈々生様をお守りいたします
We will-o'-the-wisps shall guard you all day long today.
Hey, Momozono.
（飛田）
ねえ 桃園さん
ち… 違うの この子たちは
I-It's not what you think! These kids are...
Is Tomoe not coming to school today?
今日は巴衛君は休みなの？
Well, uh... What?
Oh yeah, he's not. That's right.
そ… そう 休み　休みです
（鬼切）
大丈夫でございます 奈々生様
No need to worry, Lady Nanami.
Normal people cannot see us.
（虎徹）人に我らの姿は見えませぬ
（奈々生）えっ？
Huh?
妙だな
How odd.
鳴神が
こちらに来るかと思ったのだが―
I thought Narukami was headed this way,
but the rainclouds have passed completely.
雨雲が通り過ぎてしまった
俺の思い過ごしか
Perhaps I was worried for nothing.
The clouds have moved toward Nanami's school.
雲の流れた先は奈々生の学校
Surely not...
まさかな
（奈々生）
鬼切君たちが
お弁当持ってきてくれて助かった
Thanks for bringing my lunch. You guys are real lifesavers.
So good!
うーん おいしい
Tomoe is such a good cook.
にしても巴衛って料理上手よね
Was Mikage a gourmet or something?
ミカゲさんが
よっぽどグルメだったのかな
（虎徹）
いえ 神も我らも
基本 食事の習慣はないのです
Oh, no. Neither we nor gods are in the habit of partaking of meals.
Your body is of flesh and blood,
（鬼切）
奈々生様が生身の体ゆえ―
あれで巴衛殿も毎日勉強しつつ
料理に励んでおられるのです
so despite how it seems, Master Tomoe studies daily as he devotes himself to cooking for you.
I had no idea.
そうなんだ
Master Tomoe always thinks of you first.
（鬼切）
巴衛殿はいつでも
奈々生様 第一に考えておられます
I'm worried for you.
（巴衛）
お前が心配なのだ
Stop that! There's no way that's true!
やめてよ そんなわけないって
（鬼切）
いやいや
巴衛殿は奈々生様のことを
But it is. Master Tomoe's regard for you is...
こら
女の子をからかっちゃ駄目だぞ
Hey, you shouldn't tease a girl like that.
You are Momozono Nanami?
桃園奈々生ですね
A spirit?! Huh?
妖怪？　あれ？
邪魔をされぬよう結界を張りました
この中にいるのは我々のみ
I have erected a barrier so that we are not disturbed.
We are the only ones in here.
I am a god who maintains a shrine up in the heavens.
私は天に社を持つ神
雷神 鳴神姫です
I am Lady Narukami, god of thunder.
I have heard of the events that
led to you becoming a land god.
あなたが土地神になった
いきさつは聞いています
It must've been hard on you to have this grave responsibility thrust upon you.
無理に負わされた重責
さぞ苦労があったことでしょう
その苦労も今日で終わり
Your troubles end today.
I shall take over the Mikage Shrine in your place.
そなたに代わり この鳴神が
ミカゲ社を引き継ぎましょう
（奈々生）
苦労？
Troubles?
I shall free you of that hardship.
私が そなたを
苦労から解き放ってあげましょう
You've got it all wrong. I'm not troubled by anything.
いいえ 鳴神様
私 苦労なんてしてません
I mean, I have the will-o'-the-wisps and Tomoe.
社には鬼火わらしも巴衛もいて
みんな 優しくて
They're wonderful to me.
I actually think of the shrine as my home now.
私は社を自分の家だと思っています
だから私 社を出たくはないんです
So I don't want to leave the shrine.
Unacceptable!
（鳴神姫）そんなの駄目
（奈々生）えっ？
Huh?
Nanami!
奈々生！
Tomoe!
（奈々生）巴衛！
（巴衛）無事か
Are you all right?!
I see you've come, Tomoe.
（鳴神姫）
来ましたね 巴衛
Master Tomoe!
（鬼切）巴衛殿
（虎徹）奈々生様が
Lady Nanami is...
Narukami, what in the world is going on here?
鳴神
これは一体どういうことなのか
Release Nanami.
奈々生を放してほしい
その娘は俺のあるじだ
She's my lady and mistress.
こんな小娘があるじとは
落ちたものですね　巴衛
This weak little girl is your lady and mistress?
How far you have fallen, Tomoe.
Wh-What should I do? Tomoe!
（奈々生）
ど… どうしよう 巴衛
人間に隷従している
お前を見ているといらいらします
It irritates me to see you submitting to a human!
That is none of your business!
余計なお世話だ！
I knew something like this would happen, so I
borrowed the Lucky Mallet from Lord Daikokuten!
こんなこともあろうかと
大黒天様から借りてきた打出(うちで)の小槌(こづち)
What?!
Here we go!
そ～れ 小さくな～れ
Minify!
Wha—
（巴衛）な…
（奈々生）巴衛！
Tomoe!
Tomoe?!
巴衛？
And you're next!
次はお前だ
Release
What?
Mikage's mark belongs to me now.
ミカゲの印 確かに頂きました
With that, you are no longer a land god.
これでもう
そなたは土地神ではない
Go and live your life, human. You may now do so as befits someone in your humble position,
これからは分相応に―
人の子として けなげに
つつましく生きていくのですよ
Nanami.
奈々生
Tomoe!
巴衛！
Tomoe, if you wish to be restored
to your old self, come to the shrine.
巴衛 元に戻りたければ
社へいらっしゃい
私の神使になるなら
戻してあげましょう
If you will become my familiar, I shall restore you.
Hang in there, Tomoe!
しっかりして 巴衛
Now, will-o'-the-wisps, show me the way.
（鳴神姫）
さあ 鬼火わらし
私を案内しなさい
Yes, ma'am.
（鬼切･虎徹）ははっ
（奈々生）えっ？
What?!
Lady Nanami, we are so very sorry. We are spirits of the shrine.
（鬼切）
奈々生様 申し訳ありません
我らは社の精
We have no choice but to serve our new lady and mistress.
（虎徹）
社の主に付き従わねばなりません
Well then, a good day to you.
それでは ごきげんよう
I guess we're both homeless now, huh?
帰る場所なくなっちゃったね 巴衛
私はお金持ってないし
巴衛はちっこいし
And I'm completely broke.
dirt
poor
And Tomoe's so tiny.
little
runt
これから どうしよっか
What should we do now?
You should do as you please.
（巴衛）
お前の好きにすればいい
ここは人間の世界だろう
This is the world of humans, is it not?
As a human, you will find a place for yourself in no time at all if you put your mind to it.
人間のお前なら その気になれば
居場所などすぐ見つかる
I no longer have the ability to look after you.
俺では
もうお前の面倒を見ることは
Conk
あっ
巴衛 どうしたの 巴衛！
Conk
Tomoe! What's wrong?!
あっ すごい熱 どうしよう
巴衛 どうしよう
He has a terrible fever!
What'll I do?!
Tomoe! What'll I do?!
Closed for
consultations
for the day.
I'm such an idiot.
ばかだ 私
Tomoe's not human, so even if I got him to a doctor, what's the point?
巴衛は人間じゃないのに
病院に連れてきたって
He's so hot. At the very least, I need to find a place where he can sleep safely.
熱い　せめて ちゃんと
寝られる場所を見つけないと
Nanami?
（鞍馬）奈々生？
（奈々生）あっ
What are you doing out here?
（鞍馬）
こんな所で何してんの
（奈々生）あっ
（鞍馬）あれ お前…
Hey, hold on.
What happened to your mark?
土地神の印は？
He's turned into an awfully cute little thing, hasn't he?
随分かわいらしくなったもんだな
そいつ
I know you had to stay home
because you weren't feeling well,
（奈々生）
鞍馬も体調不良で休んでるのに
急に押しかけてごめんね
so I'm sorry for barging in on you.
体調不良？
ああ 仕事で休む口実だよ
Not feeling well?
Oh, that was just an excuse to miss class.
Our school's less than sympathetic to the plight of this talented pop star and the work he must do.
あそこは
人気アイドルに―
Popular
理解のある
学校じゃないから―
Popular
手続き面倒なんだ
But to be fair, they've probably never had someone as famous as yours truly enrolled at their school.
何せ超人気アーティストが
入学するなんてこと―
Super
Popular
今までなかっただろうからね
Super
Popular
Hey, you're a crow spirit, aren't you?
鞍馬って 天狗(てんぐ)の妖怪だったよね
Super
Popular
Hey! Stop calling me that all the time!
お前 あんまし
天狗 天狗言うなよ
俺は堕天使で売ってんだからよ
I'm making my name as a fallen angel!
ねえ 妖怪を診てくれる
お医者さん知らない？
Well, do you know a doctor who treats spirits?
I'm afraid that won't help much.
医者を呼んでも無駄だ
What?
（奈々生）えっ？
（鞍馬）完璧に体だけ退行してる
He's been regressed in body only.
His original spirit powers aren't setting in and are going out of control.
だから 元の妖力が体に収まらず
暴走してるんだ
That's what's causing his fever.
（鞍馬）発熱の原因はそれだよ
（奈々生）じゃあ
Then...
（鞍馬）
元の体に戻さないと治らないな
He won't get better unless he's restored to his old body.
If you will become my familiar, I shall restore you.
私の神使になるなら
戻してあげましょう
This'll only be a temporary fix, but it's worth a shot.
（鞍馬）
一時しのぎだが
とりあえず気つけ薬だ
It's an old secret remedy that's
been passed down in my family.
俺のけん族に伝わる
由緒正しい秘薬だぜ
Grudge Over
Ostrich Incident
You better be grateful for this pill, fox.
Grudge Over
Ostrich Incident
ありがた～く１粒頂戴しろよ
きつね
Grudge Over
Ostrich Incident
It's bitter as hell, though.
すんげえ苦いけどな
Grudge Over
Ostrich Incident
Chomp
（鞍馬）
ダッテ～ン！
Fallen!
Tomoe...
（奈々生）
巴衛
よかった 少し落ち着いたみたい
What a relief.
He seems to be resting easier.
Get well soon.
早く 良くなってね
（雪路(ゆきじ)）
ほら ささ餅をやろう
Here, you can have a bamboo-leaf rice cake.
Yukiji...
（巴衛）
雪路
俺は
I...
巴衛
よかった 目が覚めたんだね
Tomoe...
Oh, good! You're finally awake!
Squeeeeze
I give up!
Squeeeze
I was so worried!
心配してたんだよ
Squeeeze
Aren't you thirsty? Is there anything you want?
のど渇いてない？
何か欲しいものとかある？
I want to eat...
ささ餅が食べたい
bamboo-leaf rice cake.
Kurama!
（奈々生）鞍馬！
（鞍馬）うん？
（奈々生）台所とお金貸して
（鞍馬）金！
I need your kitchen and some money!
Money?!
（鞍馬）
へえ
ささ餅の作り方なんか知ってるのか
So you actually know how to make bamboo-leaf rice cake?
昔 お母さんが
よく作ってくれたから
My mother used to make it for me all the time.
He's never asked me for a single thing before.
あの巴衛がさ
私に頼み事したんだよ
So I'm happy to oblige.
何か うれしかったんだよね
How is it?
おいしい？　巴衛
奈々生特製のささ餅だよ
I made them just for you.
Average.
普通
I guess he's normal Tomoe on the inside.
やっぱ中身は いつもの巴衛か
Nanami.
（巴衛）奈々生
（奈々生）えっ？
Huh?
ありがとう
Thank you.
どういたしまして
You're welcome.
I'm really coming down with something, so I won't be at school today.
体調不良で欠席します
寝冷えと心労で
right up
Next part coming
Next
part
starting
Next
part
starting
Next
part
starting
Next
part
starting
Next
part
starting
It's raining!
（小竹(こたけ)･小梅(こうめ)）
雨です！　雨漏りでございます！
The roof's leaking everywhere!
何です この ぼろ神社は！
What kind of pathetic shrine is this?!
We're so very sorry.
（虎徹）
申し訳ありませぬ
（鬼切）
管理していた巴衛殿の妖力が
及ばなくなったため―
Master Tomoe had been maintaining it with his spirit powers,
社が元の姿に戻ったのでございます
so without him, the shrine's reverted to its original state.
Of course.
（鳴神姫）
巴衛　すぐ音を上げて―
I don't know why I believed that fox would ever give up and come running back here.
私の所へ
駆け込んでくると思ったのに
Koume! Kotake!
（鳴神姫）小梅 小竹
（小梅･小竹）はっ
Ma'am!
Bring me Tomoe!
（鳴神姫）巴衛を迎えにお行き
（小梅･小竹）御意！
As you wish!
Fuzzy
Wuzzy
（奈々生）
何これ
ふさふさしてて くすぐったい
What is this?
Fuzzy
Wuzzy
It's fuzzy but tickles at the same time.
Kurama!
（奈々生）鞍馬！
（鞍馬）誰だ うるさいな
Who's calling? What a racket.
何で あんたと一緒に寝て…
Why was I sleeping with you?
Oh
!
Last
Night
人のベッド占領して何泊する気だ
ソファーで寝ろ
Last
Night
How many nights are you gonna
stay here?! You took over my bed!
Go sleep on the couch!
Then would you sleep with Tomoe in the bed?
じゃあ
ベッドで巴衛と寝てくれる？
Yeah, right!
誰が寝るか
Tumble
That damn fox can sleep on the floor!
こんなきつね 板の間に転がしとけ
Tumble
You're a different story. I don't mind you in my bed.
女の子となら添い寝してやっても
Screech
Thump
Gouge
You goddamn fox!
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
（鞍馬）このくそぎつね！
（奈々生）こら やめろ！
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Hey! Stop that!
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Thump
Gouge
Screech
Exhausted Sleep
（奈々生）
あのまま寝ちゃったんだ
女子として何という失態
And I just fell asleep after that!
Tasaki?
What a terrible faux pas for a girl to make!
What do you want at this hour?
Wake up call? I never asked for that.
Remember that he's a spirit.
あの男は妖怪だ
Tomoe! How do you feel?
（奈々生）
巴衛 具合どう？
少しは警戒しろ
Try to be on your guard.
What did you say about me?
誰が何だって？
Are you okay going wakey-wakey alweady, wittle boy?
僕ちゃん
もう おっきして大丈夫なの？
Noogie
It wooks wike your teething fever hasn't gone down yet.
知恵熱
まだ下がってないみたいでちゅよ
Noogie
Don't be so rough with him!
巴衛に乱暴しないで
Getting a girl to come to your defense like that? Not bad.
そうやって女の子に
かばってもらって いい格好だな
You're the reason she's here in the first place.
奈々生がうちにいるのは
お前のためだってこと 忘れんなよ
Don't forget that.
He has the right of it.
（巴衛）
全くだ
きついのは熱のせいじゃない
What pains me is not the fever.
This is so irritating.
いらいらする
巴衛を元の姿に戻さなきゃ
We have to get Tomoe back to normal.
If he became small because of the Lucky Mallet,
打出の小槌で
小さくなったんなら―
you'll probably have to use it to make him big again.
打出の小槌で
大きくするしかないだろうな
You need to get your hands on that mallet.
そいつを手に入れればいい
鞍馬が
鳴神から取ってきてくれると
Could you go get it from Lady Narukami?!
（鞍馬）おっと もう こんな時間
（奈々生）どこ行くの？
Oh my, look at the time.
Where are you going?
Rehearsal for a live performance at ten o'clock.
（鞍馬）10時からライブのリハでね
（奈々生）そっか
I see.
Someone looks awfully forlorn.
心細いって顔してんぜ
Wh-What? No, I don't.
し… してないわよ そんな顔
Here's the spare key to my house,
my cell phone number, and some money.
家のスペアキーと
俺の携帯番号と金 置いとくから
（奈々生）えっ
（鞍馬）何かあったら連絡しな
What?
If anything happens, give me a call.
（奈々生）
あ… ありがとう
Th-Thank you.
巴衛　私ちょっと
スーパー行ってくるけど―
Tomoe.
I'm going to run some quick errands.
Is there anything you need?
何か必要なものある？
Useless Good-For-Nothing
Tomoe?
巴衛？
I shall go too.
俺も出る
もう大丈夫だ
I feel fine now.
The reason I feel irritated is because of this body.
いらつくのは この体のせい
What about school?
（巴衛）お前 学校は
（奈々生）えっ？
What? Today's Saturday, so there's no school.
今日は土曜で休みだよ
それより巴衛を元に戻すほうが
Getting you back to normal is more important, anyway.
（巴衛）
お前はお前のことを考えろ
俺のことは俺が何とかする
You should think about yourself.
I shall take care of my own affairs.
You shall?
（奈々生）
何とかって…
I don't know how you can. You're way too tiny.
どうすんのよ
こんな小さいくせに… あっ
Slap
You have been restored to your human self,
お前は人に戻ったんだから
人として生きるべきだ
so you should live as a human.
俺は俺の好きに生きる
I can and will live as I please.
Tomoe...
（奈々生）
巴衛
I wonder if he's planning to go to Narukami.
もしかして巴衛 鳴神の所に
Splat
あっ　ちょっと大丈夫？
熱上がってんじゃん
Splat
Hey, are you okay?! Your fever's gotten worse!
（小梅）巴衛殿
（小竹）捜しましたよ
Master Tomoe!
We have been searching for you!
We have come to bring you back, Master Tomoe.
（小梅）
巴衛殿をお迎えに参りました
Lady Narukami is concerned for your
well-being and awaits you at the shrine.
（小竹）
鳴神様が巴衛殿の身を案じて
社でお待ちしております
After what she did to Tomoe, she has some nerve saying she's concerned!
巴衛をこんなにしておいて
身を案じるなんて よく言うわね
私と巴衛はもう 同じ家を追われた
家族みたいなものだから―
Tomoe and I are like family, and we've been driven from our home together.
It doesn't matter if I'm human amd he's a spirit!
人間とか あやかしとか
そんなの関係ない
I'm gonna find a way to take care of him.
巴衛のことは私が何とかする
（奈々生）うう…
（巴衛）何もできないくせに―
How are you supposed to help me
when you can't even help yourself?
お前に俺が
助けられるわけないだろう 奈々生
巴衛
Tomoe...
To live life burdening you...
お前に背負われて生きるなど
考えただけでいらつく
The thought enrages me.
You there, lion-dogs. Take me to the shrine.
おい こま犬 社に行く
連れていけ
Yes, sir.
（小竹･小梅）
はい
Are you really... going?!
本当に… 行っちゃうの？
What pains me more than anything is being seen by her while I'm in this pathetic state.
（巴衛）
きつかったのは 多分―
こんな自分を
お前に見られていたせいだ
Farewell, Nanami.
さようなら 奈々生
To...
Tomoe, you jerk!
巴衛のばか！
Oh, dear. They split up just like that.
（乙比古）
あらら あっさり別れちゃったわね
What now?
どうする？
Rub
Oh, Tomoe! I've been waiting for you!
巴衛 待っていましたよ
Rub
フフフッ
私には分かっていますよ 巴衛
I already know.
In the end, you have nowhere else to go but this shrine.
お前は結局
この社以外に行き場がないことを
（ミカゲ）
行く所がないなら
僕の社にいるといいよ
If you have nowhere to go, you can stay at my shrine.
Now, offer up your life to me
さあ その命をささげ―
and become my personal possession for all eternity!
未来永ごう
私の所有物となりなさい
さあ 私と神使の契約を
Now seal the contract and be my familiar...
What?!
Tomoe, where did you go?!
巴衛 どこ行った～！
Nanami.
（鞍馬）
奈々生
Well, well. You've got quite
the honor guard here for you.
これはこれは
大層なお迎えが来てるな
Honor guard?
（奈々生）お迎え？
（鞍馬）いや
Nothing. Why are you doing sitting out here?
どうした こんな所に座り込んで
鞍馬を待ってたの
お世話になりました
I was waiting for you. I wanted to thank you for your help.
Bow
Tomoe went back to the shrine.
巴衛が社に帰ったの
鳴神の神使になるんだって
I guess he decided to become Narukami's familiar.
私じゃ 止められなかったよ
I wasn't able to stop him.
You can't even help yourself.
（巴衛）
何もできないくせに
I couldn't do anything—
（奈々生）私 何にもでき…
（鞍馬）んなことで泣くなよ
There's no point crying over a little thing like that. Come on.
めんどくさいな
な… 泣いてないわよ
I-I'm not crying!
What do you mean "a little thing"?!
（奈々生）そんなことって何よ
（鞍馬）しかたないな
All right.
Here's a parting gift for you since
you've gone back to being human.
人に戻っちゃったお前に
俺からのせん別だ
By having a physical piece of a spirit,
人の目に見えないものも―
you can see all the things that are invisible to the naked eye.
あやかしの体の一部を
所有することで見えるようになる
羽根？
A feather?
Lady Nanami!
（鬼切･虎徹）
奈々生様！
Onikiri! And Kotetsu too!
鬼切君 虎徹君も
When did you get here?!
いつの間に？
さっきから ずっと隣で泣いてたぜ
They've been crying next to you all this time.
（虎徹）
大変なのでございます
We're in deep trouble!
巴衛殿が鳴神様を避けて
社へお隠れに
Master Tomoe has evaded Lady
Narukami and hidden in the shrine!
It has greatly angered her, and at this rate, she is practically ready to destroy us, shrine and all!
鳴神様は大変お怒りで―
このままでは
社ごと潰しかねない勢いなのです
Lady Nanami, please save Master Tomoe and the shrine!
（鬼切）
奈々生様
巴衛殿を社を助けてください
お前に俺が
助けられるわけないだろう 奈々生
How are you supposed to help me?
Okay, let's go!
うん すぐ社へ
We have the Night Fog Carriage waiting.
（鬼切）夜切車(よぎりぐるま)を待たせております
（虎徹）さあ お乗りくだされ
Come, please get on.
Can I borrow your feather?
（奈々生）鞍馬 羽根借りるね
（鞍馬）返さなくていいよ
Don't worry about it. Just be careful.
（鞍馬）気を付けて
（奈々生）ありがとう
Thank you.
でやーっ！
Wh-Whoa...
We cannot find him!
（小竹･小梅）
見つかりませぬ！
The attic!
（小梅）屋根裏も
（小竹）床下も
Under the floors!
（小竹･小梅）
捜したんですけど！
We searched it all!
Curse you, Tomoe. Make a fool out of me, will you?
おのれ巴衛
この私をこけにしおって
Since it has come to this...
こうなったら―
I have no need of this rundown shrine anymore!
こんなぼろ社 もういらぬ
消し炭にしてくれる！
I will burn it to cinders!
（奈々生）こらー！
（鳴神姫）うん？
Hey!
What kind of twisted god tries to destroy her own shrine?!
神様が自分の社を壊して
どうすんだっつうの！
You! Why are you here?
（鳴神姫）
お前 なぜここに
巴衛なら隠れて見つからぬ
If you're looking for Tomoe, he's gone into hiding.
Yeah, well,
私なら
巴衛がどこに隠れてるかくらい―
I can easily find where he's hiding.
見つけられるけどね
You are a mere human! You could not possibly find him!
（鳴神姫）
人のお前に捜せるはずがないわ
Then if I find him, swear to me that you'll turn him back to normal.
（奈々生）
じゃあ もし私が見つけたら―
巴衛を元の姿に戻すと
約束してくれる？
いいでしょう
Very well.
Just you watch. I'll find him for sure.
絶対に見つけてみせるわ
I can't find him.
Discouraged
One Hour Later
見つからない
He might've passed out because of his high fever.
巴衛 あの高熱で倒れてるのかも
Lady Nanami?
（鬼切）
奈々生様？
これ
This...
That is Lord Mikage's pocket mirror.
（鬼切）
それはミカゲ様の懐鏡でございます
（奈々生）
鏡の中から感じる
I can feel it from inside the mirror.
巴衛の体温
Tomoe's body heat...
It's so hot.
熱い
I found him.
見つけた
巴衛
Tomoe.
Let's go home together.
一緒に帰ろう
So he hid within a mirror belonging to the previous land god.
（鳴神姫）
先代 土地神の
鏡の中に隠れていたとは―
That is quite the show of faithfulness.
随分 操を立てられたものだ
If you will not be mine,
私のものにならないのなら―
I do not want you.
いらぬ
Return
to Lord
....Daikokuten
（小梅）
ついでに このぼろ社も
いらぬということで
She also doesn't want this rundown shrine, so...
It's up to us to return the mallet and the mark.
（小竹）
小槌と み印を
お預かりしてまいりました
Ugh
What kind of excuse is that?! Bring her back here!
何その言い分
鳴神 ここに連れてこい！
At any rate, we shall return the mark.
とにかく 印はお返しします
体が光ってる
My body... is glowing!
With that, the mark of the land god is yours, Lady Nanami.
（小竹）
これで土地神の印は
奈々生様のものでございます
Please swing the mallet.
小槌をお振りくださいませ
Say, "Grow bigger," as you face Master Tomoe.
巴衛殿に向かって
大きくな～れと
This is your job, Lady Nanami.
奈々生様のお仕事でございます
Okay.
大きくな～れ！
Grow bigger!
I am restored.
戻った
Your hair has grown at the same time.
（虎徹）
髪も一緒に伸びてしまいましたな
What's wrong?
（巴衛）何だ
（奈々生）何でもありません！
Nothing at all!
何で私が巴衛に
Why am I feeling this way about him?
わあ 雨上がったみたい
上がったね 雨上がりまくってるね
Wow, it looks like the rain's let up!
It let up! It totally let up!
（奈々生）わあ すごいすごい
（巴衛）借りが出来たな
Wow! That's awesome! So awesome!
It seems I owe you.
What?
えっ
そうよ 感謝してよね
That's right. You do.
You have my thanks.
最上級の感謝
The contract between us is resealed.
神使の再契約だ
I think that was his way of promising that we'd always be together.
（奈々生）
それは
ずっと一緒の約束の印
kamisama onegai da
Please, God
boku no
I...
ano hito ni aitai no sa
I want to meet her
ah ah ah
ah ah ah ah
kamisama tsurain da
God, I'm in pain
kyou mo mata nou ni
Because, she...
konakatta
didn't come today either.
onegai ga aru no kamisama
I have a request, God
boku wo tasukete
Please, save me
ah ah ah ah
kamisama mou osoi
God, it's too late for me
Preview
ano ko wa...
Because she's...
（講釈師）
風邪をひいてしまった
奈々生に代わって―
Nanami has ended up catching a cold, so Tomoe
disguises himself as her and goes to school in her stead.
Touku sora ni
gone off into the distant sky
巴衛が
奈々生に化けて登校することに
そこに鞍馬が近づいてきて…
And that is when Kurama makes his move.
Kieta no sa
and disappeared
Meanwhile, Mizuki comes to see Nanami.
一方 奈々生の所には瑞希(みずき)が
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Next time, "The God Catches A Cold."
The God Catches A Cold
次回「神様、風邪をひく」
Sayonara baby
Farewell, baby
Achoo.